in henryfyfe nfyfe

SUMMARY

I am a full-stack web developer, passionate about helping others problem solve, creating intuitive user experiences, and learning about the world through data. My experience focused on newer companies as I love to build, whether company, application, or circuit board.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: Ruby, Rails, Python, Java, Javascript, JQuery, HTML / CSS, PHP, Hadoop / Hive, SQL, R, Matlab **SOFTWARE & PLATFORMS:** Tableau, Google Analytics, Amplitude, Wordpress & WooCommerce, Shopify, Oracle, VBA / Excel

PROJECTS

RASPBERRY DRIVE

Use a Raspberry Pi 3 with camera to drive an RC Car. I implemented controls of the car from the Pi, including the board output, wiring, and simple server for receiving commands.

LABSHARE

A sample Rails application for sharing experiment proposals across all members of a lab. I implemented the test suite, achieving 96% coverage.

EDUCATION

Princeton University

BSE Operation Research & Financial Engineering Magna Cum Laude GPA: 3.8 departmental, 3.73 overall Varsity Water Polo

VOLUNTEERING

TRINIDAD & TOBAGO WATER POLO

Summer 2009

· Assistant Coach

Implemented training program for U-16 Men and U-14 Women National teams. Coached both at 2009 Central American and Caribbean Championships in Barquisimeto, Venezuela.

EXPERIENCE

DEV BOOTCAMP

Chicago Jul 2016 to Nov 2016

Student

• A 19-week intensive training program for aspiring web developers, with a focus on building full-stack web development skills using Test Driven and Agile development

techniques while practicing empathetic team cooperation and communication.

• Languages covered: Ruby & Rails, Javascript & JQuery, HTML5 / CSS, and Python.

CONSULTANT

Chicago Mar 2016 to Current

Ginoseast.com

- Redesigned purchasing experience of the existing Ginoseast.com online shop (an installation of Woocommerce). Revised site layout and refactored back-end products & orders SQL database. Debugged and upgraded integrations with vender.
- Designed & developed a web presence for Bravo's loyalty and gift card programs. Wrote client and server components (javascript & php) that securely integrated with NCR's APIs for its loyalty and gift card products.

Butterfly Network

New York City Jan 2016 to May 2016

 Advised on best practices for eCommerce systems and processes. Developed a roadmap for business operations growth (vendors, systems, and staffing) based on stated product and business goals. Reviewed extant operating systems.

SOUARE

San Francisco Sep 2014 to Dec 2015

Business Associate - eCommerce Growth

• Manager for growth of Square's payments hardware eStore on web and mobile. Responsible for measuring and reporting on conversion rates via Google Analytics and Ruby/MySQL/Tableau. Identified funnel optimizations and design revisions and

and LTV acquired by 120% and 100% respectively over 15 months. • Led investigation of enterprise eCommerce platforms for potential use by Square. Presented an analysis of eCommerce platforms to executive team.

managed engineering team in executing improvements. Increased channel revenue

Business Operations Manager

- Managed Square's global fulfillment & distribution operation with \$10 million in annual spend. Consolidated US operations from 3 vendors to 1, and expanded operations into Canada and Japan. Oversaw onboarding of vendors.
- Launched supply / demand planning process for all products in Square's supply chain, including Square Stand, Square Reader, and 3rd party Point-of-Sale devices.
- Evaluated supply-chain ERP platforms and project managed implementation of Oracle's Supply Chain solution across internal and external teams.

Business Intelligence Analyst

Oct 2012 to May 2013

- Created operating metrics for segments of the customer onboarding funnel using MySQL, Ruby ETLs, and Tableau. Implemented process for measuring warehouse turn-around and shipping times. Identified improvements that reduced average order-to-delivery time by 24%.
- Designed and implemented system (the physical recording processes, MySQL & Hadoop databses and Ruby & Python ETLs) for tracking products through the supply chain to facilitate better understanding of how customers acquired devices.

NOMURA SECURITIES

Desk Analyst - Capital Markets

New York City Jun 2010 to Jun 2012

- US oil-and-gas and basic materials equity trading analyst, covering 18% of the S&P 500. Analyzed financial statements and sensitivities to commodity prices to identify investment opportunities and risks. Distributed a daily commentary note to clients.
- Developed methodology and systems for tracking team's profit & loss by trading counterparty (clients) using Excel VBA and Microsoft Access.